Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Irish Americana Collection AIA.031.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Irish Americana Collection
1817-1995
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Moloney, Mick (Michael)
AIA.031.004
51.75 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 4 manuscript boxes, and 55 oversize flat boxes.
This collection of Irish-American ephemera and published music is part of the larger Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Collection. This subcollection consists of sheet music, songsters, jokebooks, advertisements, and other forms of printed ephemera documenting the Irish and Irish-American image in American popular culture during the 19th and 20th centuries, with particular emphasis on ethnic perceptions and representations.
Arrangement
This subcollection is arranged into seven series. Series are arranged alphabetically by title or subject. Series VII has not been arranged by an archivist.
Missing Title
I: Sheet Music (Irish), 1817-1995
II. Songsters and Song Albums, 1863-1960
III. Sheet Music (Non-Irish), 1847-1946
IV. Jokebooks, 1883-1928
V. Postcards, 1900-1915
VI. Ephemera, 1856-1960
VII: Unprocessed, undated
Historical/Biographical Note
Dr. Mick Moloney (1944-) is a musician, folklorist, and Global Distinguished Professor of Music and Irish Studies at New York University. He immigrated to the United States in 1973, earning a Ph.D. in folklore and folklife from the University of Pennsylvania. He has recorded and produced over forty albums of traditional music, acted as advisor for scores of festivals and concerts, and served as artistic director for the musical ensemble The Green Fields of America. In 1999, Moloney was awarded the National Heritage Award of the National Endowment of the Arts, the highest official honor of traditional artist can receive in the United States. Moloney is the author of Far from the Shamrock Shore (2002) and numerous essays on Irish music and musical culture, and the co-editor of Close to the Floor: Irish Dance from the Boreen to Broadway (2009).
Sources: Steve Winnick, "From Limerick Rake to Solid Man: The Musical Life of Mick Moloney," Dirty Linen, No. 48 (October/November 1993) 1999 NEA National Heritage Fellowships: http://www.nea.gov/honors/heritage/fellows/fellow.php?id=1999_11 Mick Moloney, Musician and Folklorist: http://www.mickmoloney.com
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Custodial History Note
New York University's Division of Libraries, in conjunction with Glucksman Ireland House at New York University, purchased the Mick Moloney Collection for the Archives of Irish America in 2006. Until the Collection was transferred to New York University, under the supervision of Dr. Michael Nash, Head of the Tamiment Library, the materials were stored in Dr. Moloney's house in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 2006.071 and 2010.019.
Related Archival Materials
The Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Collection is composed of five parts. Taken together, they illustrate Dr. Moloney's career long engagement with Irish-American culture across a wide variety of media with a particular focus on Irish and Irish-American music.
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Commercial Recordings (AIA 031.1)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings (AIA 031.2)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Papers (AIA 031.3)
Mick Moloney Irish American Music and Popular Culture Photographs (AIA 031.5)
Dorothy Hayden Cudahy Irish Memories Collection (AIA 001)
Archives of Irish American Newspapers and Periodicals Collection (AIA 004)
Susan McKeown Papers (AIA 032)
Scope and Content Note
The Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Irish Americana Collection is a subcollection of the larger Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Collection consisting of printed ephemera and published music documenting the Irish and Irish-American image in American popular culture during the 19th and 20th centuries, with particular emphasis on ethnic perceptions and representations. The subcollection includes both positive and negative stereotypes of the Irish, as depicted on sheet music, postcards, and other commercial printed materials such as songsters, joke books, advertisements, and cartoons. Materials in this collection were published between 1817 and 1995, with the majority dating from between 1860 and 1930. The market for such commercial paper products was tied to the simultaneous emergence and symbiotic relationship of the American middle class and the culture of consumption during this period. In addition, the seepage of entertainment from public venues such as vaudeville into the domestic sphere created demand for such materials.
Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Songbooks.; Sheet music.; Postcards.; Advertising cards.; Jestbooks.; Irish Americans.; Irish Americans -- Music.; Caricatures and cartoons.; Irish -- Songs and music.; Ball, Ernest R, 1878-1927; Harrigan & Hart; Brennan, J. Keirn, 1873-1948; Pease, Harry, 1886-1945; Murphy, Stanley, 1875-1919; Von Tilzer, Harry; Von Tilzer, Albert; Hoffmann, Max, 1873-1963; Bryan, Alfred, 1871-1958; Schwartz, Jerome; Tilzer, Harry Von, 1872-1946; Morse, Theodore F., 1873-1924; Hobart, George V. (George Vere), 1867-1926; Cohan, George M. (George Michael), 1878-1942; Costello, Bartley, 1871-1941; Schwartz, Jean, 1878-1956; Olcott, Chauncey, 1858-1932; French, Percy, 1854-1920; Moloney, Mick (Michael)
- Series I: Sheet Music (Irish), 1817-1995, 191937
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: Sheet Music (Irish), 1817-1995 consists of sheet music focusing on songs about Ireland and the Irish published in the United States, particularly in New York City. The majority of the titles in this series were printed between 1860 and 1930, with a significant number of undated pieces. A variety of genres (from comic to sentimental) are documented, as well as a recurring cast of composers, lyricists, and publishers. Together, they offer a comprehensive look at what was an musical form of cultural expression and an extremely lucrative business between the American Civil War and the Second World War.
  Among the men composing music for Irish-themed sheet music who are substantially represented in this series are David Braham (28 examples), Jerome Schwartz (17), Ernest R. Ball (16), and Harry Von Tilzer (14), in addition to Victor Herbert, Theodore F. Morse, Albert Von Tilzer, Max Hoffman, and Walter Scanlan. There are "Irish" lyrics penned by Edward Harrigan (27), William Jerome (21), Alfred Bryan (13), and Bartley Costello (13), as well as by Thomas Moore, Samuel Lover, George V. Hobart, Harry Pease, J. Keirn Brennan, and Stanley Murphy. George M. Cohan and Chauncey Olcott represent composers who were also lyricists.
  The team of Harrigan and Hart aside, only Cohan and Olcott are familiar names. Nevertheless, one of the men defining the "Irish Colleen" through sheet music such as that in Series I was Alfred Bryan (1871-1958), a native of Ontario who moved to New York in 1905. Among the thousand songs he composed were "My Irish Girlie" (Box 28, Folder 31) and "Peg O'My Heart" (Box 32, Folder 18). His philosophy was simple: "the public wants something that sings well."
  More than 1,000 songs resulted from the collaboration of lyricist William Jerome and composer Jean Schwartz, among them many of the most memorable Irish-American pieces of the Tin Pan Alley era. The son of Irish immigrants, William Jerome Flannery (1865-1932) was born in Cornwall-on-the-Hudson, New York. After stints as a dancer with McAvoy's Hibernicon and Barlow's Minstrels, he starred during the 1890s at Tony Pastor's Theatre on 14th Street and at E. F. Albee's Union Square Theatre in New York City. Shortly after the turn of the century, Jerome turned to songwriting, teaming up with Jean Schwartz (1878-1956), a native of Budapest who began his New York career demonstrating pianos for a department store. Their first Irish American hit was "Bedelia" (Box 3, Folder 31) in 1903, followed two years later by "My Irish Molly O" (Box 28, Folder 35).
  Novelty and nostalgia dominate Series I, with the most popular themes taking love and emigration as their subjects; see, "The Day I Left Old Erin (For the Good Old U.S.A.)" (Box 6, Folder 22), "Sing an Irish Song To-Night (For Your Old Daddy)" (Box 35, Folder 12), or "3,121 Miles Away" (Box 1, Folder 1). Words were often used to convey "Irish" at a glance and the Tin Pan Alley composer who sprinkled his lyrics with well-known Irish place names — "The Tipperary Twirl" (Box 39, Folder 8), "My Little Cottage Home in Sweet Killarney" (Box 29, Folder 13), "I'm On My Way to Dublin Bay" (Box 15, Folder 21) — conjured up an image of a mythical land of green fields and quaint villages that bore little relation to contemporary Ireland.
  "'Twas Only an Irishman's Dream" (Box 39, Folder 22) or "Wait till I Lay My Hands on McNally!" (Box 40, Folder 1) are examples of titles in the sentimental and comic Irish repertoire. Humorous songs based on now-outdated conceptions of ethnicity took up the controversial theme of the "amalgamation of races," usually depicted through musical examples about romance and marriage between the Irish and other ethnic groups written within a narrow time period at the turn of the twentieth century. There are six songs about Irish men romancing Native American maidens — such as "Minni-Ha-Ha-Donahue" (Box 26, Folder 10) — two depicting Irish-Asian alliances — "When Chu-Ching-San Weds Paddy McCann" (Box 40, Folder 12) and "My Little China Doll" (Box 29, Folder 12) — as well as those featuring Mexicans, African-Americans, Italian-Americans, and Jews, like 1925's "Kosher Kitty Kelly" (Box 23, Folder 3).
  Sheet music cover illustrations that represent the Irish as simianized, such as "The Judge, He's-a-Irish Too!" (Box 21, Folder 6) and "Come Down, Mike Downs, Come Down" (Box 5, Folder 27). The lyrics of many songs in Series I stereotype the Irish and Irish-Americans with racial or prejudiced language and situations. Other songs incorporate terms of endearment from the Irish language like "mavourneen," "acushla," "astore," and "machree." Particularly interesting examples can be found in "Carrigdhoun" (Box 5, Folder 1) and "Let the Farmer Praise His Grounds" (Box 24, Folder 1).
  Contemporary events are also reflected in the subject matter, especially Irishmen serving as soldiers with the American military. "The Wild Irish Boy" (Box 42, Folder 17), "Somewhere in France Dear Mother" (Box 36, Folder 11), and "The Army's Full of Irish" (Box 2, Folder 34) date from the First World War while "Johnny Doughboy's Found a Rose in Ireland!" (Box 21, Folder 2) was a 1942 hit for singer Kate Smith, the same year "Clancy's Gone and Joined the Army" (Box 5, Folder 11) was published.
  The oldest sheet music in Series I is "Eveleen's Bower" (1817) and the most recent is "The Irish Wedding Song" (1995). Of political interest are "Far Away Ireland" (1986), which is dedicated to Ronald Reagan, complementing "When Ireland Takes Her Place among the Nations of the Earth" (1919), which is dedicated to Eamon de Valera. The bulk of the sheet music was published in the United States, with New York City dominant, but there are good samples from Boston, Chicago, and Philadelphia. Among the foreign publications, there are 142 examples from London — such as "The Eyes of Irish Blue" (1913) — and 14 from Dublin, including Percy French's "The Emigrant's Letter" (n.d.). Many of the pieces are in excellent condition, considering their great age, but the majority have frayed along the spine and have separated. Only the pieces "Her Danny" (Box 12, Folder 27), "Nora Machree" (Box 30, Folder 14), "Shadowland" (Box 34, Folder 12), and "Winging Your Way to Ireland" (Box 42, Folder 19) are incomplete or contain a possibly unrelated page.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Materials in Series I are in the process of being digitized and currently unavailable to researchers. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with further questions.
  - Numeric, 336043
    - 3,121 Miles Away, undated; 193251 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A, 336042
    - A Bit O' Blarney, 1904; 193250 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A Bit O' Pink and White, 1923; 193249 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A Bit O' the Brogue, 1920; 193248 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - A Bit of Irish, 1923; 193247 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A Breath of Old Ireland and You, 1920; 193246 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A Broken Song, 1904; 193245 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - A Broth of a Boy, 1922; 193244 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - A Flower from Irish Soil, 1899; 193243 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - A Garden in Connemara, 1949; 193242 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - A Laugh with a Tear in It, 1908; 193241 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - A Little Bit of Heaven, 1907-1916; 193240 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - A Little Bit of Irish, 1911; 193239 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - A Little Bunch of Shamrocks, 1913; 193238 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - A Little Dash of Dublin, 1935; 193237 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - A Little Drop of Irish and a Wee Bit of Scotch, 1919; 193236 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - A Picture of Dear Old Ireland, 1916; 193235 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - A Puff O' Me Pipe and A Song, 1922; 193234 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - A Real Irish Mother, 1920; 193233 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - A Rose of Old Derry, 1907; 193232 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - A Shawl of Galway Grey, 1949; 193231 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - A Sprig O' Shillalah, 1904; 193230 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - A Wee Bit o' Love, 1929; 193229 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - A Wee Little Drop o' the Cruiskeen Lawn, 1912; 193228 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - A Wee Sprig of Green, 1957; 193227 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Abie's Irish Nose, 1925; 193226 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Abie's Irish Rose, 1947; 193225 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Abie's Irish Rose (2), undated; 193224 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Acushla, 1906; 193223 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Acushla Mine, 1948; 193222 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Acushla! I'm Calling Thee, 1914; 193221 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - After the Ball, undated; 193220 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Aggie Asthore, 1858; 193219 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Agricultural Irish Girl, The, 1949; 193218 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Ah, Sweet is Tipperary, 1921; 193217 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Airs of Old Erin, undated; 193216 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Airy Mary, 1919; 193215 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Alice Fitzgerald, 1888; 193214 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Alice O'Grady, 1906; 193213 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - All Aboard for Ireland, 1919; 193212 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - All for the Love of Mike, 1922; 193211 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - All Hands Went on Strike, 1893; 193210 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - All My Life, 1936; 193209 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - All That I Want is in Ireland, 1920; 193208 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Allan's Irish Pianist, undated; 193207 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Along the Rocky Road to Dublin, 1915; 193206 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - America to Ireland, 1868; 193205 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - America, Ireland Loves You, 1917; 193204 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - An Irish Christmas, 1949; 193203 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - An Irish Coquette, 1905; 193202 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - An Irish Courtship, 1903; 193201 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - An Irish Dance, 1930; 193200 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - An Irish Girl, 1973; 193199 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - An Irish Girl is Good Enough for Me, 1909; 193198 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - An Irish Girl's Bouquet, 1892; 193197 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - An Irish Girl's Lament, 1905; 193196 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - An Irish Lad's Wooing, 1895; 193195 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - An Irish Love Song, 1895, 1898; 193194 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - An Irish Noel, 1904; 193193 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - An Irish Slumber Song, 1903; 193192 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - An Irish Song Will Live As Long As Life and Love Shall Last, 1921; 193191 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - An Irishman Was Made to Love and Fight, 1918; 193190 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - An Old Irish Lady, Apr 1905; 193189 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - And That's How We Love in Ireland, Mar 1905; 193188 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Angels Whisper, undated; 193187 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Answer to the Lament of the Irish Immigrant, The, Jan 1905; 193186 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Any Old Place the Gang Goes, 1918; 193185 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Are Ye Right There, Michael?, 1902; 193184 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Are You for Ireland?, 1921; 193183 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Are You the O'Reilly?, 1915; 193182 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Army's Full of Irish, The, 1917; 193181 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Arrah Arabia, 1908; 193180 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Arrah, Come in Out of the Rain, Bernie McShane, 1909; 193179 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Arrah Go On I'm Gonna Go Back to Oregon, 1916; 193178 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Arrah Wanna, 1906; 193177 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - As I Walk Home With Kitty Malone, 1904; 193176 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - As Irish As Dublin Town, 1947; 193175 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - As Long As the Shamrock Grows Green, 1912; 193174 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Asthoreen Bawn, 1946; 193173 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - At the Cry of the First Bird, 1924; 193172 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - At the Donnybrook Fair, 1916; 193171 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - At the End of an Irish Moonbeam, 1927; 193170 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - At the Meeting of the Waters, 1920; 193169 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Away, Bonnie Bark, undated; 193168 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Away From You, 1925; 193167 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - B, 336041
    - Back Again to Dear Old Ireland and You, 1915; 193166 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bad Luck to the Day, 1870; 193165 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Back in Tipperary Town, 1917; 193164 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Babies on Our Block, The, 1879; 193163 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Ballymaquilty Band, The, 1948; 193162 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Ballymoney Conversazione, The, undated; 193161 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Bard of Armagh, The, 1914; 193160 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Barney, 1903; 193159 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Barney A'Leen, 1871; 193158 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Barney Brallaghan, undated; 193157 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Barney Come Over Here, 1920; 193156 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Barney McCoy, 1881; 193155 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Barney M'Coy, 1882; 193154 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Barney O'Hea, undated; 193153 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Barney, Take Me Home Again, 1875; 193152 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Beautiful Girl of Kildare, 1873; 193151 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Beautiful Isle of Erin, 1915; 193150 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Beautiful Norah, undated; 193149 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Because You're Irish, 1917; 193148 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Bedelia, 1903; 193147 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Begorrah, 1959; 193146 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Believe Me, If All Those Endearing Young Charms, 1910; 193145 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Bells of Killarney, 1913; 193144 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Bells of Killarney (2), 1927; 193143 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Bells of Shandon, The, 1878; 193142 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Bells of St. Mary's, The, 1917, 1942; 193141 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Be My Tipperary Bride, 1912; 193140 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Bendeemer's Stream, 1893; 193139 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Be Sure and Kiss the Blarney Stone, 1916; 193138 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Be Sure He's Irish, 1912; 193137 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Biddy, 1920; 193136 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Biddy Maloney, 1874; 193135 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Birds, The, 1906; 193134 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Birth of the Shamrock, The, 1923; 193133 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Blarney, 1937; 193132 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Blarney Dream, The, 1938; 193131 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Blarney Kate, 1911; 193130 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Blarney Song, The, 1917; 193129 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Blarney Stone, 1949; 193128 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Bless You Darlin' Mother, 1936; 193127 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Blime Me, O'Reilly, 1915; 193126 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Blue Waves Are Sleeping, The (An Irish Folk Tune), 1964; 193125 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Bowl'd Sojer Boy, The, undated; 193124 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Box of Shamrocks, The, 1859; 193123 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Boys of Kilkenny, The, undated; 193122 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Boys of the County Cork, The, 1946; 193121 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Brannigan's Band, 1876; 193120 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Brian Og and Mollie Bawn, c. 1950; 193119 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Bridget O'Flynn, 1926; 193118 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Bring back the Roses, 1918; 193117 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Bringing Up Father in Society, 1915; 193116 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - By the Little Old Log Cabin, 1919; 193115 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - By the Shores of the Irish Sea, 1916; 193114 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - C, 336040
    - Callahan's Gang, Carmel Quinn, 1893; 193113 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Carrigdhoun, undated; 193112 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Casey, 1911; 193111 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cash! Cash! Cash!, 1881; 193110 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 'Cause it's You, Just You, 1922; 193109 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Celtic Fisherfolk Song, 1942; 193108 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Change O'Mind, 1921; 193107 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Charleston Blues, The, 1882; 193106 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Chimmie Fadden, 1895; 193105 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Christmas in Killarney, 1950; 193104 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Clancy Lowered the Bloom, 1948; 193103 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Clancy's Gone and Joined the Army, 1942; 193102 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Clara Nolan's Ball, 1885; 193101 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Cleopatra McNally, 1890; 193100 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Cockles and Mussels, 1949; 193099 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Colleen, 1905; 193098 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Colleen (2), 1939; 565205 (Box 5, Item 16)
    - Colleen Avarra, 1898; 193097 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Colleen Bawn, 1906; 193096 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Colleen I'm Calling to You, 1917; 193095 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Colleen My Own, 1925; 193094 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Colleen O'Mine, 1920; 193093 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Come Back to Connemara, 1907; 193092 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Come Back to Erin, 1908-1942, nd; 193091 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Come Back to Erin, Mona Darling, 1916; 193090 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Come Back to Me, 1917; 193089 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Come Back to Old Ireland, 1922; 193088 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Come Down McGinty, 1904; 193087 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Come Down, Mike Downs, Come Down, 1901; 193086 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Come Kiss the Blarney Mary Darling, 1911; 193085 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Come on Over Here, It's A Wonderful Place, 1916; 193084 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Connemara Shore, The, 1926; 193083 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Contrary Mary Clary, 1915; 193082 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Coortin' in the Kitchen, 1942; 193081 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Copper Malone, 1890; 193080 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Cordalia Malone, 1904; 193079 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Core of my Heart, undated; 193078 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cot Where My Old Dad Was Born, The, 1912; 193077 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Countess Markievicz, 1935; 193076 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - County Mayo, 1947; 193075 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Cross Your Fingers Maggie Flynn, 1916; 193074 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Cruiskeen Lawn, undated; 193073 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Cuishla Machree, undated; 193072 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Cushlamachree, 1937; 193071 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - D, 336039
    - Daddy's Irish Melodies, 1914; 193070 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Daisy Donohue, 1903; 193069 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Dan Mulligan's Masquerade, 1880; 193068 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Dancing 'Neath the Irish Moon, 1915; 193067 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Dancing Time in Kerry, 1923; 193066 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Daniel O'Brien and Young Paddy O'Shea, 1925; 193065 (Box 6, Folder 17)